Bangkok time on December 31st 2017 and
like you know we wanted to get something
out before New Year's but then like the
demo
it ended up like breaking up pretty
quickly you know it was early days but
since then of course it's not early days
anymore and at the start of 2018 a
really massive effort started to
actually build out the ethereum proof of
St system and to build out the ethereum
scaling system which has since then
turned into the blobs that we have today
2022 the merge switching from proof of
work to proof of steak
2024 The Surge part one right so if you
look into the road map diagram and you
look into the search section you see
that there's two Milestones there's one
that I call Basic rollup scaling and
there's one that I call full rollup
scaling and basic rollup scaling
basically says you need major ler 2os to
hit stage one and you need blobs to
exist and so 2024 we actually hit that
the next step is having actual like
fully running data availability sampling
and major ear 2 is hitting stage two so
I think that will happen and I think
that will happen sooner than people
and it's up to the ler 2 teams to build
this future of ethereum there are still
a lot of problems that are left to solve
so we want upgrades to decentralization
who here wantsum to be
decentralized who here wants ethereum to
be
centralized okay okay so one person
wants ethereum to be
centralized okay um censorship
resistance wants to censor
ethereum okay a couple more hands um
Quantum resistance who here wants
ethereum to break the first time a Quant
of computer comes
out okay one hand that's good you know
maybe it's like you know you know
sometimes like you need collapse in
order for Renewal to happen right so
further upgrades to make sure that
decentralization sensorship resistance
and Quantum resistance continue
happening Progressive upgrades to
efficiency and scale um so so Layer Two
I think is going to scale extremely
quickly and its safety is going to
improve quickly over the next few years
and also I expect Progressive upgrades
cautious upgrades but still Progressive
and definitely ongoing upgrades to layer
one capacity in different forms as well
over the over the next years and I think
one of the big reasons why we need to do
this one is to support the activity that
continues to happen on layer one itself
and two because ultimately if something
breaks on a layer two layer one still
needs to be there to be as a back stop
and so the maximum theoretical safe
capacity of l2s is proportional to to
the capacity of L1 we're going to have
upgrades to data availability sampling
to increase the number of blobs that
ethereum can support as of about a week
ago ethereum is actually hit price
discovery mode meaning the uh in terms
of blobs meaning that the number of
blobs that is actually being us being
used on ethereum exactly equals the
protocol that long-term Target now we
need to scale this number upgrades are
happening to actually do this so
upgrades to data availability sampling
we've now we have also scaled enough
that a wide variety of applications are
possible ens consumer payments social
one category that I think is going to be
extremely important over the next decade
is mixed financial and non-financial
applications applications that make use
of the power of Finance But ultimately
to serve ends that go be that go beyond
financial goals and I think there's lots
of very powerful applications here and I
think it's uh we've spent a long time
making the technology better and we will
continue doing this but it is at the
level where now is the time to build
thank you
[Applause]